Guide to the Lillian D. Wald Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Lillian D. Wald Papers,
1895-1936
Wald, Lillian D., 1867-1940.
ca. 30,000 items (96 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079444
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Corresponcence
Series III: General Subjects
Series IV: Children
Series V: Henry Street Settlement
Series VI: Labor Relations
Series VII: Nursing
Series VIII: Peace Movement
Series IX: Public Health
Series X: Russia
Series XI: Settlements (other than Henry Street)
Series XII: Oversize
Biographical Note
Director of Henry Street Settlement in New York City. Miss Wald retired from active directorship in 1932.
Scope and Content
Papers concerning both the administration of the Henry Street Settlement and Wald's involvement in numerous philanthropic and liberal causes. Her office files trace the foundation and growth of the Henry Street Settlement from 1895 until 1933. Her other activities include child welfare, civil liberties, immigration, public health, unemployment, and the peace movement during World War I. The correspondence files contain letters from public figures and writers including Jane Addams, Roger N. Baldwin, Van Wyck Brooks, Lavinia L. Dock, John Galsworthy, Samuel Gompers, William D. Howells, Charles Evans Hughes, Mabel Hyde Kittredge, Frances Perkins, Dorothy Thompson, Norman Thomas, Ida Tarbell, Margaret Sanger, and Jacob A. Riis.
This collection has been published in microfilm by Research Publications, Inc.
The microfilm comprises 112 microfilm reels and is availible in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
Subjects
Henry Street Settlement (New York, N.Y.); Addams, Jane, 1860-1935.; Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Dock, Lavinia L., 1858-1956.; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933.; Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924.; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Kittredge, Mabel Hyde, 1867-1955.; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965.; Thompson, Dorothy, 1893-1961.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944.; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966.; Riis, Jacob A. (Jacob August), 1849-1914.; Charities--New York (State)--New York.; Social settlements--New York (State)--New York.; Social service--New York (State)--New York.; Child welfare.; Civil rights.; Emigration and immigration.; Public health.; Unemployment.; Peace.; World War, 1914-1918.; Women social workers.
Boxes 12-97 are offsite. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1967 M-67 Visiting Nurse Service through Mrs. Eva M. Reese Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Addams, Jane to LDW; 9 May 1901 - 17 November 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 47)
    On Reel 1 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Addams, Jane to Women's Peace Party; 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Addams, Jane to LDW; 25 January 1919 - 28 January 1919 (Box 1, Folder 49 to 50)
  - Addams, Jane to Karl O. Hesley; II January 1933 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Adler, Felix to LDW; 22 September 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aladin, Alexis to LDW; n.d. -21 March 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 19)
  - Aldrich. Chester Holmes to LDW; 16 October n.y. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alger, George W. to LDW; 10 March 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angell, James Rowland to LDW; 16 October 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angell, James Rowland to Mary S. Gardiner; 9 December 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Angell, James Rowland to LDW; 6 January 1921 -17 April 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3 to 6)
  - Baker, Newton D. to Amos Pinchot; 9 January 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baker. Newton D. to LDW; 26 June 1917 -13 October 1919 (Box 1, Folder 2 to 4)
  - Balch, Emily Greene to LDW; n.d. -18 May 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Balch, Emily Greene to Dorothy Caffin; 27 March 1919 -I April 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Balch, Emily Greene to LDW; 25 December 1919 -[January 1931] (Box 1, Folder 6 to 12)
  - Baldwin, Charles M. to LDW; 24 May 1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash to LDW; May 1917 -30 June 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash to Eleanora Iredale; 22 August 1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash to LDW; 10 September 1917 -9 March [1933] (Box 1, Folder 6 to 24)
  - Barnard, Kate to LDW; 12 October 1908 -15 January 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Barrows, Isabel Hayes Chapin to LDW; 5 May n.y. -21 March 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Battle, George Gordon to LDW; 18 November 1913 -17 June 1918 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 7)
  - Battle, George Gordon to Beulah Weldon; 22 June 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Battle, George Gordon to LDW; 6 February 1919 -25 March 1920 (Box 1, Folder 9 to 12)
  - Battle, George Gordon to Elizabeth Cullen; 21 June 1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Battle, George Gordon to LDW; I May [1915]-4 May 1915 (Box 1, Folder 14 to 15)
  - Battle. George Gordon to Anne E. Geddes; 12 May 1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Battle, George Gordon to LDW; 6 April 1927 -28 October 1929 (Box 1, Folder 17 to 22)
  - Baum. Marie to Bertha B. Carter; 27 August 1931 -28 September 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Beard, Mary Ritter (Mrs. Charles A.) to LDW; 22 February 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beard, Mary Ritter (Mr. Charles A.) to Miss Hitchcock; 27 August 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bech, Georg to Karl O. Hesley; 13 April 1931 -16 April 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Belmont, Eleanor Robson (Mrs. August) to LDW; 17 March 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone to Catherine V. Breshkovsky; n.d. (Box 1)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone to LDW; 9 August 1911 -29 May 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2 to 12)
  - BlackweU, Alice Stone to Paul Kannady; II September 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone to LDW; IS September 1917 -20 February 1928 (Box 1, Folder 14 to 33)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone to LDW; 28 February 1928 -27 February 1929 (Box 1, Folder 34 to 38)
    On Reel 2 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Blackwell. Alice Stone to Miss A,A. Bliss; 3 March 1929 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Blaine, John J. to LDW; 23 February 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blanchard, Paul and othe .. to Karl O. Hesley; 17 March 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce to Bertha L. Darling; 24 December 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce to LDW; 10 September 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 3 Bliven. Bruce to Karl D. Hesley; 8 April 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - I Bonham carter, Henry to LDW; 15 July 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - I Booth, Evangeline Cory to LDW; 12 March 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Booth, William Stone to LDW; 22 October 1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borslum, Gutzon dela Mothe to LDW; n.d. -24 February 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Brace, Donald Clifford to LDW; 17 May 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brandeis, Louis O. to LDW; 9 October 1911 -16 January 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Breshkovsky. catherine Verigo to various people; 1910 -1919 & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to LDW; 11 September 1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to Alice Stone Blackwell; 21 February 1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to LDW: 10 April 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to Alice Stone Blackwell; 13 October 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to LDW; 20 April 1917 -23 August 1919 (Box 1, Folder 6 to 10)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to (Helena S. Dusley?]; 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to Helen S. Dudley; 7 February 1926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Breshkovsky. Catherine Verigo to Mr. & Mrs. Arthur Bullard; 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Breshkovsky, Catherine Verigo to LDW; [December 1926) -25 February 1931 (Box 1, Folder 14 to 17)
  - Brooks, John Graham to LDW; n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck to LDW; 10 March 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bruere, Henry to LDW; 23 July 1914 -[March 1933) (Box 1, Folder 1 to 15)
  - Bruere. Jane Monroe (Mrs. Henry) to LDW; [February 1926] -20 February (1926) (Box 1, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Bullard, ArthUr to LDW; 2 January 1919 -31 March 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to LDW; 20 September 1902 -3 November 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1 to 9)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to Herbert H. Lehman; 10 April 1920 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to LDW; 20 April 1920 -15 October 1920 (Box 1, Folder 11 to 13)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to Elizabeth A. Cullen; 29 October 1921 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to LDW; 22 December 1923 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to Felix M. Warburg; 30 March 1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burlinghnm, Charles C. to LDW; 10 April 1926 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to Mabel Coleman; 10 June 1926 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to LDW; 13 December 1926 -8 January 1927 (Box 1, Folder 19 to 22)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to Mabel Coleman; 14 January 1927 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Burlingham, Charles C. to Karl O. Hesley; I September 1932 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Carlton, Newcomb to Jacob Henry Schiff; 7 February 1916 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Carlton, Newcomb to LDW; 18 August 1926 -IS February 1928 (Box 3, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Cbapin, Henry Dwight to Jean Rosborough; 13 January 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chapman, John Jay 10 LDW; 14 January 1904 -10 July 1908 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Chaykovsky, Barbara 10 Isabel Chapin Barrows; 3 February 1908 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chaykovsky, Barbara to LDW; 10 February 1908 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chaykovsky, Barbara to Alexis Aladin; 18 February 1908 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chaykovsky, Barbara to LDW; 20 February 1908 -24 April 1908 (Box 3, Folder 4 to 9)
  - Cbaykovsky. Barbara to Joseph M. Price; 12 September 1908 -16 September 1908 (Box 3, Folder 10 to 11)
  - Chaykovsky, Barbara to LDW; 28 December 1915 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chaykovsky, Nikolai Vasilyevich to LDW; 12 November 1908 -6 April 1909 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Chaykovsky. Nikolai Vasilyevich to Joseph M. Price; 28 May 1909 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chaykovsky. Nikolai Vasilyevich to LDW; 28 May 1909 -24 February 1910 (Box 3, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Chaykovsky. Nikolai Vasilyevich to Joseph M. Price; 141aouary 191 I (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chaykovsky,NikolaiVasilyevich toLDW; 14 January 1911-12 February 1911 (Box 3, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Chaykovsky. Nikolai Vasilyevich to Alice Stone Blackwell; 13 February 1911 May 20, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Chaykovsky, Nikolai Vasilyevich to LDW; 20 January 1915 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chaykovsky. Nikolai Vasilyevich to Joseph M. Price; 16 May 1915 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chaykovsky, W. (Mrs. Nikolai V.) to LDW; 21 December 1907 -28 January 1908 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Claessens, August to LDW; 28 April 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Claessens. August to Helen Hall; 14 September 1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cobden-Sanderson, Anne Cobden (Mrs. Thomas J.) toLDW; (3 January 1908)30 April [1926] (Box 3, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Coler, Bird S. to LDW; 7 March 1901 -S February 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 7)
  - Condon, Randall J. to LDW; 10 April 1925 -5 June 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 3)
    On Reel 3 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Condon, Randall J. to Anne E. Geddes; 10 June 1925 -10 September 1925 (Box 3, Folder 4 to 10)
  - Conley, William G. to Karl D. Hesley; 14 April 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Copeland, Royal Samuel to LDW; 12 February 1920 -18 May 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Copeland, Royal Samuel to Anna HeUyer; [January 1929] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Copeland, Royal Samuel to LDW; 9 January 1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Copeland, Royal Samuel to Karl O. Hesley,ll February 1933 -22 March 1933 (Box 3, Folder 5 to 7)
  - Copeland, Aaron to LDW; 3 March [1928] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Crain. Thomas C.T. to LDW; 12 December J921 -IS November ]930 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 9)
  - Crain, Thomas C.T. to Karl O. Hesley; 23 October 1931 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Crosby, Ernest Howard to LDW; n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Crosby, Emest Howard to YsabelIa Waters; 20 May 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Crosby, Grace Ashton to LDW; 16 March n.y. -4 June n.y. (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Crosby, (Dame) Rachel Eleanor to LDW; 18 April 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Damrosch, Frank Heino to LDW; 9 July 1906 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Davis, James J. to LDW; 31 March 1924 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Davis~ Robert Courtney to Lydia Banning; 27 December 1922 -26 January 1923 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
  - DeForest, Robert Weeks to LDW; 26 April 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Devine, Edward Thomas to LDW; 27 March 1901 -31 August 1931 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 16)
  - Dickstein, Samuel to LDW; 13 June 1928 -I May 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Dickstein, Samuel to Karl D. Hesley; 15 April 1932 -22 March 1933 (Box 3, Folder 3 to 9)
  - Dix, John Alden to LDW; 16 August 1911 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dock, Lavinia L. to LDW; 2 March R.y. -26 December (1903) (Box 3, Folder 1 to 8)
  - Dock, Lavinia L. to [Mary MacDow.lI~ 30 December (1903) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dock, Levinia L. to LDW; I F.bruary (1904) -10 March 1916 (Box 3, Folder 10 to 27)
  - Dock, Levinia L. to Anne E. Geddes; [192S) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dock, Lavinia L. to LDW; 27 April 1925 -10 May 1925 (Box 3, Folder 29 to 31)
  - Dodge~ Cleveland E. to Katrina Mackenzie; 26 May 1920--18 June 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Dodge, Cleveland E. to the Henry Street Settlement 1 May 1922 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dodge, Cleveland E. to Josephin. Schain; 26 May 1922 -24 May 1923 (Box 4, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Dodge, Clev'land E. to Karl D. Hesley; 27 July 1932 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Downing, Bernard to LDW; 6 March 1929 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dublin, Louis I. to LDW; 9 March 1933 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - DuBois, W.E. Burghardt to LDW; I July 1918 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dulles. Eleanor Lansing to LDW; 10 November 1928 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dulles, Eleanor Lansing to Bertha B. Carter; 22 November 1928 -2 December (1929) (Box 4, Folder 2 to 8)
  - Dulles, Eleanor Lensing to Rolla H. Southworth; S December 1929 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dun, Angus to LDW; 16 November 1919 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Duveen. Joseph, Baron Duveen to LDW; n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Earhart, Amelia to Karl D. H ....y; 10 December 1928 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Easttnan, Max to LDW; I December 1917 -[August 1928) (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Ely, Richard Theodore to Florence Kelley; 20 May 1905 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ely, Robert Erskine to LDW; 26 January n.y. -II March 1933 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 14)
  - Embree, Edwin R. to LDW; 22 January 1919 -2 May 1924 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Embree, Edwin R. to Naomi DeulSh; 31 July I92S (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Emerson. Anna Seelye to LDW; n.d. -13 September 1901 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Evans, Montgomery, 2nd to LDW; 14 March 1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Farrell, Elizabeth E. to ?; n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Farrell, Elizabeth E. to LDW; n.d. -2 March 1911 (Box 4, Folder 2 to 7)
  - Farrell, Elizabeth E. to William H. Maxwel~ 17 November 1911 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Farrell, Elizabeth E. to LDW; 14 September 1912 -[May I92S) (Box 4, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Finley, John Huston to LDW; 31 May n.y. -5 April 1928 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 9)
  - Fisher, Irving to LDW; 2S July 1929 -2S June 1930 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Folks, Homer to LDW; II February 1907 -18 May 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 9)
  - Folks, Homer to Viola P. Conklin; 28 June 1920 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Folks, Homer to LDW; 7 July 1920 -12 1ar 1923 (Box 4, Folder 11 to 15)
  - Folks, Homer to LDW; 2 December 1924 -9 March 1933 (Box 4, Folder 16 to 34)
    On Reel 4 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Forbes-Robertson, Sir Johnston to LDW; 9 November 1919 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ford, Henry to LDW; 2S November 1915 -27 November 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson to Karl O. Hesley; 9 May 1932 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Furse, (Dame) Katherine Symonds to LDW; 30 May 1926 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Furst, Clyde to LDW; 30 January 1919 -13 April 1927 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip to LDW; 30 October 1919 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip to Emma B. Sayre; 26 December 1919 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gale, Zona to LDW; 13 December [1915] -4 May 1916 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Galsworthy, John to LDW; 23 February n.y. -27 March [1919] (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - George, Henry. Jr. to LDW; 26 November 1910 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gibson, Irene Langhome (Mrs. Charles Dana) to LDW; 12 [October 1926] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Giddings, Franklin Henry to Paul U. Kellogg; 16 January 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gilder, Helena de Kay (Mrs. Richard W.) to LDW;[1911]-19November 1911 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson to LDW; 19 August 1908 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gildersleeve, Virginia C. to LDW; I February 1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Goldman, Emma to LDW; 2 July 1904 -9 September 1917 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Goldman, Emma to 1; 4 November 1920 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Goldman, Emma to LDW; 7 June 1928 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gompers, Samuel to LDW; II April 1917 -24 July 1918 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Green, Fred W. to LDW; 16 May 1929 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Greenslet, Ferris to LDW; 19 December 1914 -31 December 1914 (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Greet. (Sir) Philip Barling Ben to LDW; 21 March[1911]-13November[1931] (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Guilbert. Yvette to LDW; 27 December 1918 -[March 1919] (Box 4, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Hackett, Francis to LDW; 18 April 1926 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hall. Bolton to LDW; 4 January 1904 -12 May 1927 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Hand. Frances Amelia Fincke (Mrs. Learned) to LDW; 7 March 1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harcourt, Alfred to LDW; 24 December 1914 -13 May 1915 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 9)
  - Harcourt, Mary Ethel Burns. Viscountess Harcourt to LDW; S November 1921 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hardie. James Keir to LDW; 24 January 1909 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harkn.... Edward S. to LDW; 25 May 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harriman. Florence Jaffray Jones (Mrs. J. Borden) to LDW; 10 January 1911-11 September 1920 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Haskell, Henry S. to LDW; 31 July 1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hayward, Walter B. to LDW; 22 August 1917 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hearst, Millicent Willson (Mrs. William Randolph) to [LDWt 22 June 1918 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hecht, George J. to Dorothy Coffin; 24 March 1919 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hecht, George J. to LDW; 2 March 1920 -8 October 1920 (Box 5, Folder 2 to 7)
  - Hecht, George J. to Viola P. Conklin; 20 January 1921 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hecht, George J. to LDW; 9 June 1921 -21 February 1930 (Box 5, Folder 9 to 25)
  - Heckscher, August to LDW; 26 August 1926 -18 November 1926 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Hendrick. Burton Jesse to LDW; 30 March 1915 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hewitt, Abram S. to Virginia Potter; 28 March 1901 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hillquit, Morris to LDW; 5 May 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hitchcock, Edward to [LDW]; 24 December 1901 -[December] 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Hitchcock, Helen Sanborn Sargent (Mrs. Ripley) to LDW; 4 March 1929 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hitchcock. Ripley to LDW; 16 December 1914 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Holmes, Lois Moxon (Mrs. T.O.) to LDW; 1894-1909 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Homer, Louise Dilworth Beatty to LDW; 31 March [1926] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hoover, Herbert to Mrs. Gray Griswold; 25 January 1918 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hoover. Herbert to LDW; 3 June 1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - House. Edward Mandell to LDW; 9 April 1917 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - House. Loulie Hunter (Mrs. Edward M.) to LDW; 27 March (1917J (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Howells, William Dean to LDW; 4 January 1904 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Huebsch, Benjamin W. to [LDWt 28 March 1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans to LDW; 26 August 1907 -28 September 1922 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Hunt. Joseph Howland to Public Nurse Service; 24 March 1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hurst. Fannie to LDW; 10 March 1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jay. Pierre to?; S October 1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jerome, William Travers to LDW; 4 March 1902 -13 June 1907 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Johnson, Alvin Saunders to LDW; 2 May 1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, James Weldon to LDW; I October 1919 -14 July 1921 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Johnson, James Weldon to Elizabeth A. Cullen; 6 December 1921 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Johnson. James Weldon to LDW; 22 December 1922 -14 December 1928 (Box 5, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood to LDW; 2 May 1917 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jordan, David Starr to LDW; 6 March 1917 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kahn, Otto Hermann to LDW; 5 March 1906 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kelley, Florence to LDW; n.d. -6 September 1917 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 11)
  - Kelley, Florence to LDW; [May 1925) -9 February 1926 (Box 5, Folder 12 to 13)
    On Reel 5 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Kelley, Florence to Anne E. Geddes; 27 February 1926 -[May 1927] (Box 5, Folder 14 to 17)
  - Kelley. Florence to LDW; I December 1927 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Kelley. Florence to Karl O. Hesley; 28 February 1930 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Kellogg, Frank Billings to LDW; [October 1926] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kellor, Frances Alice to LDW; D.d. -6 August 1915 (Box 5, Folder 11 to 16)
  - Kennan, George to James Bronson Reynolds; 6 December 1910 -17 March 1911 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Kennan, Georse to LDW; 25 July 1912 -6 December 1920 (Box 5, Folder 3 to 5)
  - Kenyon, W.C. to LDW; 13 December 1916 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Keppel, Frederick P. to LDW; 24 January 1919 -22 April 1926 (Box 5, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Keppel, Frederick P. to [Karl O. Hesley] 18 February 1931 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Kittredge. Mabel Hyde to LDW; n.d. -4 September B.y. (Box 6, Folder 1 to 22)
  - Kittredse, Mabel Hyde to 1; 23 November n.y. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Kittredge, Mabel Hyde to LDW; 2S April 1904 -22 April 1915 (Box 6, Folder 24 to 26)
  - Kittredge, Mabel Hyde to 1; 10 August 1917 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Kittredge, Mabel Hyde to LDW; 14 April191g -II May (1925) (Box 6, Folder 28 to 31)
  - Kropotkin, (Prince) Petf Alekseevich to LDW; 8 July 1905 -10 June 1910 (Box 6, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Kropotkin. Sophie Ananiev (Princess Peter) to Mania Sukloff; 26 January 1914 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kropotkin. Sophie Ananiev (Princess Peter) to Miss Lewisohn; [1920) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - La Follette, Fola to LDW; 22 June 19O5 -7 September [19OS) (Box 6, Folder 1 to 3)
  - La Follette, Robert Marion to LDW; I May 1931 -22 May 1931 (Box 6, Folder 1 to 2)
  - La Guardia, Fiorello H. to LDW; 6 May 1926 -17 May 1926 (Box 6, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Lane. Franklin Knight to LDW; 28 November 1916 -29 December 1916 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lasker. Bruno to LDW; 7 June 1917 -2 July 1928 (Box 6, Folder 1 to 27)
  - Lasker. Bruno to Bertha B. Carter; 13 December 1928 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Lasker, Bruno to Karl O. Hesley; 21 February 1929 -2S October 1930 (Box 6, Folder 29 to 32)
  - Lasker, Bruno to LDW; 13 November 1930 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Lasker. Bruno to Karl D. Hesley; 2 February 1932 -16 December 1932 (Box 6, Folder 34 to 37)
  - Lasker, Margaret Naomi Ward (Mn. Bruno) to LDW; 13 May 1925 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lathrop, Julia Clifford to LDW; 20 January 1913 -IS November 1926 (Box 6, Folder 1 to 21)
  - Leach. Agnes Lisle Brown (Mrs. Henry G.) to Viola P. Conklin; 21 March 1917 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Leach, Agnes Lisle Brown (Mrs. Henry G.) to LDW; 14 November 1919-14 November 1922 (Box 6, Folder 2 to 5)
  - Leach, Agnes Lisle Brown (Mr. Henry G.) to Elsa H. Herrmann; 6 May 1924 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Leach, Agnes Lisl. Brown (Mrs. Henry G.) to LDW; 22 October 1926 31 January 1930 (Box 6, Folder 7 to 10)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard to Viola P. Conklin; 7 Mny 1915 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard to LDW; 14 October 1919 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard to Viola Percy Conklin; 2S October 1919 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard to LDW; S November 1919 -9 March 1933 (Box 6, Folder 4 to 10)
  - Lehman, Edith Altschul (Mn. Herbert H.) to LDW; [January 1926J -January 1926 (Box 7)
    On Reel 6 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Lehman, Herbert Henry to LDW; 23 January 1916 -23 November 1917 (Box 7)